fundsxpress.com 2004-06-04

# FundsXpress Inc.

## Privacy Policy

The operating subsidiaries of FundsXpress Inc. (“FundsXpress”) take great pride in enabling our financial institution clients and their customers or members to perform secure and convenient financial transactions over the Internet everyday. We enjoy a high level of trust and confidence from our clients and their customers, and we strive daily to justify and maintain that trust and confidence.

The employees of FundsXpress use the Internet everyday, and we too are sensitive to the privacy of our personal information when we visit the millions of Web sites that are part of the World Wide Web. Since we are Internet users, like you, it’s only natural that we would assume that you might feel the same way about the privacy of your personal information. With that in mind, we have developed the following Privacy Policy to describe the information that we collect on the Internet and to explain how we use and protect this information.

This privacy policy is directed to our financial institution clients and Website users. Section (1) describes our policy for visitors to the FundsXpress Website and Section (2) describes our policy for protecting the consumer information of our clients (the end-users of FundsXpress products). These policies are in addition to the extensive security measures that we take to protect end-user financial transactions on the Internet. Section (4) includes a discussion of these security measures.

## Visitors to the FundsXpress Inc. Website

FundsXpress does collect general information on our Website visitors simply for statistical and security purposes. Such information may include:

  * The Internet address (referral site) which brought you to our Website; 
  * The date and time you access our site; 
  * The name and version of your web browser; 
  * The Internet service provider you used when you accessed our site; 
  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address; and 
  * The pages visited in our Website. 

FundsXpress uses a cookie to collect this general information on all Website visitors. We may use this information in a consolidated, non-personally identifiable, format to assist us in offering the services and features that are of particular interest to our clients. We may also use this information to monitor the security and performance of our site.

You may elect to provide us with more specific or personal information, such as when you give us feedback or send us an email requesting additional information from our sales department. If you provide personal information to us, it is only used internally and in furtherance of the purpose for which it was provided. Please note that all visitors and clients also have the option of contacting us by telephone.

FundsXpress does have a “members only” section of the Website that’s designed to provide additional information and support to our financial institution clients. This section requires members to provide an access ID and passcode for identification and security purposes.

We do not share or sell information that we collect from visitors to the FundsXpress Website. Also, we will not send unsolicited email (spam) to our Website visitors.

FundsXpress reserves the right to monitor and make records of transactions and interchanges made over its networks, this includes failed log-on attempts in the members only section of our website. You will not necessarily be told (unless the notification is required by law) that a transaction or interchange in which you are participating is being monitored or recorded. Monitoring and recording transactions or interchanges may be initiated, for example, if we suspect a possible breach in security or some other problem that would make it appropriate to monitor or maintain these records. We do not use this information for any improper purposes or distribute it to third parties, except as required or permitted by law.

## Financial Institution Customer Information (End-Users)

As an Application Service Provider (ASP), non-public personal information of end-users may be housed or transmitted through our data center in order to provide our clients such services as Internet Banking, Lending Management, Commercial Cash Management, Portana Dynamic Websites, and Account Aggregation. End-users have high expectations for the confidentiality and privacy of their personal information. We recognize these expectations and strive to ensure that we protect the confidentiality of this information to the same extent that our client financial institutions must do.

The information provided below describes the practices that FundsXpress takes to safeguard the personal and confidential information of our end-users.

## Collection and use of end-user information

FundsXpress only collects and maintains information on the end-users of the FundsXpress’ services in order to be responsive to user needs, provide contracted services to our clients, manage our lawful business, and to maintain appropriate records. Generally speaking the information collected falls into two broad categories:

Information that is generated when a user contacts FundsXpress electronically, simply by virtue of the manner in which Internet communications are initiated and handled; and   
Information that is expressly or incidentally created in connection with a transaction or providing a service.   
An example of the information collected under (1) may include the user’s IP address and referral website, which would be logged when a consumer visits a financial institution website hosted by FundsXpress or when a consumer or end-user visits the Internet Banking gateway page. An example of the information collected under (2) might include specific customer account information, access identification information, and bill pay activity.

FundsXpress may extract from and compile non-personally identifiable end-user information collected via (1) and/or (2) in a consolidated format for statistical and research purposes. Such information might detail the number of bill pay customers, the most typical payees, the number of registered Portal customers, and the time users most frequently use our services. With respect to former end-users we only retain this information as necessary to meet our legal obligations and record retention requirements.

Similar to our policy for Website visitors, FundsXpress reserves the right to collect and monitor all transactions on our networks and applications. End-users will not necessarily be told (unless the notification is required by law) that a transaction or interchange in which they are participating is being monitored or recorded. Monitoring and recording transactions or interchanges may be initiated, for example, if we suspected a possible breach in security or some other problem that would make it appropriate to monitor or maintain these records. FundsXpress also reserves the right to disclose such information to regulatory and governmental authorities if required.

## 3rd party disclosure

FundsXpress understands that end users of FundsXpress products expect that their financial information and transactions will be handled in a confidential manner. We do not use confidential consumer information for any improper purposes or distribute it to third parties, except as required or permitted by law, or as necessary to provide a contracted service.

It is the policy of FundsXpress that non-public, personally identifiable consumer information may only be disclosed to third parties when:

The user, either directly or through our client financial institution, is believed to have requested or authorized the disclosure;   
It is necessary to administer the service or complete a transaction, such as bill pay; or   
It is required or allowed by law (such as, but not limited to, responding to a subpoena or court order, reporting information to legal authorities, regulatory agencies, or other appropriate investigators in connection with a legal investigation or similar matter).   
We contractually require our third party service providers to protect the confidentiality of the non-public consumer information received from FundsXpress. Third party service providers are only permitted to use such information for the purpose for which it was provided, such as for bill payments.

FundsXpress does provide marketing services and support to our clients in order to promote our products to the end-users. We may provide aggregate and/or consolidated end-user information to our clients to assist in marketing financial institution products and services. This service is part of the financial services package that we offer each client. Our marketing efforts are coordinated with each client financial institution and because of this, our clients are aware of and involved with any joint marketing ventures. We do not disclose any nonpublic, personally identifiable end-user information with any third party advertising firms.

## Security Features

**End-User Security**  
FundsXpress utilizes a comprehensive security strategy to protect user accounts and transactions conducted over the Internet. We use the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology for all communications with the end-user. The communication is encrypted every time an end-user enters an access ID, passcode, or personal information during an application or registration process. All financial transactions conducted by end-users are SSL encrypted. In addition, our servers have been certified by a "Certificate Authority" that will assure your customers and members that they are actually talking to our servers instead of someone pretending to be us.

**Internal Security**  
The architectural design of the system, the data center, policies, procedures, staff, hardware, and software selected for the FundsXpress systems are chosen with security in mind so that all transactions and customer information will be safe and secure. Internal security features include our Kerberos authentication software, DES and Triple DES Encryption, routers/firewalls, and real-time intrusion detection devices. Our new products will incorporate the latest security features and advanced technologies on the market.

Our secure data center protects our equipment, software, employees, as well as customer, member, and visitor information. We have established policies and incorporated many internal security systems that are designed to minimize our employees’ ability to access personal information relating to the end-users. We perform background checks on our employees, require them to sign non-disclosure agreements, and we restrict access to consumer information so that only authorized employees can access the information that is necessary to provide the contracted products and services to our clients and their end-users. All information collected from our Website visitors is also securely stored with limited employee access.

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard customer information. However, despite all our efforts related to security, like any other technology-based system, a security breach may occur. Technology relating to Internet security is evolving rapidly, as are ways to circumvent that security. Although we use state of the art security measures and take every reasonable effort to stay abreast of developments in Internet security, there is always the possibility that someone will find a way to gain unauthorized access to any system, including ours.

Our clients should contact the FundsXpress customer service department immediately if an unauthorized access is identified, even if there does not appear to be any loss involved. It is the policy of FundsXpress to investigate all such matters promptly and report intrusion attempts to the proper authorities. Electronic theft is a crime, and if we suspect that someone has attempted or perpetrated it, we would like to have your cooperation in taking the appropriate, remedial measures. In-depth information on many of the techniques and features employed by the system are detailed under our discussion of security elsewhere on this Web site.

## A Word About Cookies

A cookie is a very small text file sent by a web server and stored in your computer’s or browsers’ memory so that it can be read back later. Cookies cannot "read" information about you from your hard drive or be used to "steal" information about you. Cookies are a basic way for a server to identify the computer you happen to be using at the time, not you personally. Cookies are used for many things from personalizing start up pages to facilitating online purchases. Cookies do perform a very important function when you engage in secure Internet banking.

FundsXpress uses cookies in our products for security, statistics, and enhanced functionality. For example, with our Internet Banking product, we use a Triple DES encrypted cookie to identify the end-user’s computer while they are logged on. When a user logs on to the Internet Banking application, we send the user a cookie that enables us to process multiple transactions during the session without having to provide an access ID and passcode for each individual transaction. Users must accept this cookie to use the FundsXpress Internet Banking product. When the user logs off, or after ten minutes of inactivity, the cookie is no longer accepted and must be renewed by requiring the passcode to be reentered. A new cookie is used for each session. That way, no one can use the prior cookie to access the user’s account.

We use several cookies to provide features within our Portana and Dynamic Websites. Portana and Dynamic Website cookies are also used for security purposes and to collect general statistical information on all visitors. Portana cookies enable registered users to customize certain features, such as their stock portfolio and local weather. Portana cookies also enable the users to bypass the login process each time they revisit. These cookies only contain a unique user identification number and do not contain or collect any personally identifiable information. Users must accept most of the Portana cookies in order to view site.

When we host financial institution Websites, we also use a cookie to collect the same type of general information that we collect on this website. This information is collected for security and statistical purposes.

We do not disclose general information collected through cookies with any third party; however, we may provide consolidated, non-personally identifiable information to our clients, such as the most frequently accessed pages within a website and/or Portal, or the most frequently used browsers.

## Links

FundsXpress has a number of links to other sites. These are offered as a courtesy and a convenience to our visitors and clients. FundsXpress assumes no responsibility for the content, reliability, safety, security, or privacy practices of any such site or any transactions with respect thereto. If you have questions or concerns about any other site’s policy regarding these matters, you should contact that site or its sponsor.

## Amendments and changes

FundsXpress reserves the right to amend or change this policy at anytime. The most current version of this policy will always be posted on our Website. The effective date and version number will always be clearly displayed. This policy is for our Internet audience and our clients and does not constitute a contract nor does it modify or amend any agreement we have with our clients. The examples provided within this policy are not exclusive.

Effective: December 31, 2001

## FundsXpress subsidiaries

FundsXpress Financial Network, Inc., a Texas Corporation, is an operating subsidiary of FundsXpress, Inc., a Delaware Corporation.

## Questions

If you have any questions about this policy, please contact our customer support staff at:

1.800.419.8804 or [support@fxfn.com](mailto:support@fxfn.com).

Customer Support  
FundsXpress, Inc.  
11950 Jollyville Rd.  
Austin, Texas 78759-2309  

Copyright 2002 by FundsXpress, Inc.
